earthecho.org 2018-12-28

# EarthEcho International | Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

1.  Introduction

Thank you for visiting EarthEcho International’s websites and, if applicable, choosing to download and/or install any of our Apps.  Please read our Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy carefully, as you must agree to both documents in order to be permitted to use our Service.

2.  Definitions

Throughout this document, we may use certain words or phrases, and it is important that you understand the meaning of them.  The following is a non-exhaustive list of definitions of words and phrases found in this document:

“App” refers to our mobile software applications, including the EarthEcho Water Challenge App;

“Service” refers to the services that we provide, including our program materials, App and our Site;

“Site” refers to our websites, www.earthecho.org, www.monitorwater.org, and http://stemexplore.org/;

“User” refers to anyone who uses our Service, including users of our App, general visitors to our Site, and you;

“EarthEcho International” refers to our organization, Earth Echo International, Inc.; our Site; our App; our Service; or a combination of all or some of the preceding definitions, depending on the context in which the phrase is used;

“You” refers to you, the person who is governed by this Privacy Policy.

3.  Information Collected

Identifying Information

We collect certain personal information from you when you sign up to our Service that can be used to identify you, such as your name, e-mail address, content you submit through our Service (e.g., photos, comments, and other material) Facebook profile information, current location data, and any other information that may be relevant for the purpose of providing you with our Service or which you provide to us voluntarily. The information we collect from you, to the extent that it is private, is disclosed only in accordance with our Terms of Service and/or this Privacy Policy.  Photos or comments you submit through our Service are not private for purposes of this Privacy Policy.

Non-Identifying Information

Whenever you visit our Site or use our App, we may collect non-identifying information from you, such as your IP address, referring URL, browser, operating system, cookie information, and Internet Service Provider.  Without a subpoena, voluntary compliance on the part of your Internet Service Provider, or additional records from a third party, this information alone cannot usually be used to identify you.

4.  Use of Your Information

We may use your information to:

Enhance or improve User experience, our Site, our App, or our Service.  
Send e-mails about our Site or respond to inquiries.  
Send e-mails and updates about our Service, including our e-mail newsletter and requests for agreement to amended legal documents such as this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service.  
Send third party offers that relate directly to our Service.  
Perform any other function that we believe in good faith is necessary to protect the security or proper functioning of our Site or Service.

We may transfer your information to mWater, the creator of our App, which shall also abide by this Privacy Policy.

Photos or comments you submit through our Service are not treated as private under this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service. By using our Service, you understand and agree that photos and comments you submit may be used by EarthEcho International for any purpose and will be made publicly available.

5.  Donor Commitment

We will not sell, share, or trade our donors’ names or personal information with any other entity, nor send mailings to our donors on behalf of other organizations, with the exception of those listed above. This policy applies to all information received by EarthEcho International, both online and offline, on any platform, as well as any electronic, written, or verbal communications.

6.  Accessing, Editing, and Removing Your Information

You may in some cases be able to review and edit the personal information you have provided to us by logging into your account on the Site and editing it.  Although most changes may occur immediately, information may still be stored in a web browser’s cache.  We take no responsibility for stored information in your cache, or in other devices that may store information, and disclaim all liability of such.  In addition, we may, from time to time, retain residual information about you in our backup and/or database.

7.  Cookies

We use cookies to remember your preferences.  For this reason, it is necessary that you enable cookies in your browser, and you hereby acknowledge that we have informed you of our use of cookies and that you consent to our use of cookies in relation to your computer system.

8.  Third Party Websites

EarthEcho International may post links to third party websites on its Site.  These third party websites are not screened for privacy or security issues by EarthEcho International, and you release us from any liability for the conduct of these third party websites.

Please be aware that this Privacy Policy, and any other policies in place, in addition to any amendments, does not create rights enforceable by third parties or require disclosure of any personal information relating to members of the Service or Site.  EarthEcho International bears no responsibility for the information collected or used by any advertiser or third party website.  Please review the privacy policy and terms of service for each site you visit through third party links.

9.  Third Party Access to Your Information

Although you are entering into an Agreement with EarthEcho International to disclose your information to us, we do use third party individuals and organizations to assist us, including contractors, web hosts, and others.

Throughout the course of our provision of our Service to you, we may delegate our authority to collect, access, use, and disseminate your information.  For example, our web host stores the information that you provide us, and we may hire outside contractors to perform maintenance or assist us in securing our website.

It is therefore necessary that you grant the third parties we may use in the course of our business the same rights that you afford us under this Privacy Policy.  For this reason, you hereby agree that for every authorization which you grant to us in this Privacy Policy, you also grant to any third party that we may hire, contract, or otherwise retain the services of for the purpose of operating, maintaining, repairing, or otherwise improving or preserving our website or its underlying files or systems.  You agree not to hold us liable for the actions of any of these third parties, even if we would normally be held vicariously liable for their actions, and that you must take legal action against them directly should they commit any tort or other actionable wrong against you.

Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, you authorize us to collect, share, store, and otherwise use your information in conjunction with Facebook and Google.

10.  Release of Your Information for Legal Purposes

At times it may become necessary or desirable to EarthEcho International, for legal purposes, to release your information in response to a request from a government agency or a private litigant.  You agree that we may disclose your information to a third party where we believe, in good faith, that it is desirable to do so for the purposes of a civil action, criminal investigation, or other legal matter.  In the event that we receive a subpoena affecting your privacy, we may elect to notify you to give you an opportunity to file a motion to quash the subpoena, or we may attempt to quash it ourselves, but we are not obligated to do either.  We may also proactively report you, and release your information to, third parties where we believe that it is prudent to do so for legal reasons, such as our belief that you have engaged in fraudulent activities.  You release us from any damages that may arise from or relate to the release of your information to a request from law enforcement agencies or private litigants.

11.  Commercial and Non-Commercial Communications

By providing information to the Service that forms the basis of communications with you, such as contact information, you waive all rights to file complaints concerning unsolicited email from EarthEcho International since, by providing such information, you agree to receive communications from us or anyone else covered under this Privacy Policy.  However, you may unsubscribe from certain communications by notifying EarthEcho International that you no longer wish to receive solicitations or information and we will endeavor to remove you from the database.

12.  Security Measures

We take certain measures to enhance the security of our Service, as it is in our interest to do so.  However, we make no representations as to the security or privacy of your information.  It is in our interest to keep our website secure, but we recommend that you use anti-virus software, firewalls, and other precautions to protect yourself from security threats.

13.  Your California Privacy Rights

EarthEcho International is incorporated in the State of California and complies with the California Business and Professions Code §§ 22575-22579.  If you are a California resident you may request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to any third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  Various provisions throughout this Privacy Policy address requirements of the Californian privacy statutes.  In summary, you must presume that we collect electronic information from all visitors.  You may contact us at info@earthecho.org with any questions.

14.  International Transfer

Your information may be transferred to—and maintained on—computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction.  If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, EarthEcho International transfers Personal Information to the United States and processes it there.  Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

15.  Amendments

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time.  When we amend this Privacy Policy, we will update this page accordingly.  You must read this page each time you use our Service and your continued use of our Service shall constitute your acceptance of any such amendments.

Last Modified:  March 15, 2017
